Sabotage of Hitler's ingenious weapons of mass
destruction...the V1 and V2 rockets!
Operation Crossbow is a drama, war, thriller film directed by Michael Anderson.
Allied agents infiltrate the Nazi rocket complex at Peenemunde in
order to obtain their secrets and sabotage the plant.
The film alternates between German developments of the V-1 missile and V-2 rocket (with a German
cast speaking their own language) and discovery by British Intelligence of the weapon.
Nora Van Ostamgen, played by Sophia Loren.
Lt. John Curtis, played by George Peppard.
Professor Lindemann, played by Trevor Howard.
General Boyd, played by John Mills.
Duncan Sandys, played by Richard Johnson.
Robert Henshaw, played by Tom Courtenay.
Operation Crossbow (later re-released as The Great Spy Mission) is a 1965
British espionage thriller set during the Second World War.
This film is loosely based on an actual series of events where British undercover operatives
targeted the German manufacturing facilities for experimental rocket-bombs.
The film was directed by Michael Anderson and stars Sophia Loren, George Peppard,
Trevor Howard, John Mills, Richard Johnson, and Tom Courtenay.
The screenplay was written by Emeric Pressburger (under the pseudonym "Richard Imrie"), in collaboration
with Derry Quinn and Ray Rigby, from a story by Duilio Coletti and Vittoriano Petrilli.
It was filmed in Panavision and Metrocolor at MGM-British Studios.
Although it is largely fictional, the movie does touch on the main aspects of the operation, which was
geared to thwart the German long-range weapons programme in the final years of World War II.
The story alternates between Nazi Germany's development of the V-1 flying bomb and V-2 rocket,
and the efforts of British Intelligence and its agents to counter those threats.
All characters speak in the appropriate language, with English
subtitles for those speaking German or Dutch.
The film explores themes of nazi, rocket, metrocolor.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.